Finding Aid for Douglas Barnett photographs and scrapbooks, 1948-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Doug Barnett Photographs and Scrapbooks 1948-2001
Barnett, Douglas.
0450 Aa 2
An avid University of Michigan Hockey fan, Douglas Barnett served as official timer at hockey games from 1958 to 1983, and was a founding member of the Dekers club, a hockey booster group. The collection includes memorabilia and photographs collected over more than 40 seasons, much of it relates to the Dekers Hall of Fame. Barnett worked for the University of Michigan Mail Service and scrapbooks containing photos of mail service staff, equipment, facilities, staff events, and clippings.
2 linear feet
3 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material received May 2001 from Doug Barnett (Donor No. 9118 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
Text of January 1991 induction of Barnett into the Dekers Hall of Fame:
Doug was born and raised in Ann Arbor in the shadows of the Old Coliseum. It's no wonder his first love of sports is hockey. He skated there as a youngster and saw his first Michigan hockey game when Eddie Lowrey was still coaching. He has seen seven of the eight Michigan hockey coaches in action.
Dubbed "Mr. Michigan Hockey" several years ago by Michigan's Sports Information Department, Doug has followed Michigan hockey since 1945, when he would stand in line at the Old Coliseum to get his favorite seat behind the Michigan bench.
In 1958, Doug was asked by Don Weir, athletic ticket manager, to fill in as official timer, a position he held for twenty five years, retiring in 1983. In all these years as timer, he only missed six games for personal reasons.
Doug also served as official timer for all Ann Arbor Pioneer High School hockey games for seventeen years.
In 1962 Doug, along with eleven other loyal Michigan hockey fans, organized "The Dekers", a boosters club for Michigan Hockey. As a charter member, he served as the club's first secretary-treasurer and was honored by the members as the third recipient of the "Deker of the Year" award in 1965.
For over fifteen years Doug edited and published the Deker Newsletter, making sure all former Michigan hockey players received this newsletter six times a season. He also has been very active in organizing team reunions, including the big "Reunion of 1980" in Colorado at the Broadmoor Hotel.
One of Doug's special projects for the Dekers was obtaining all the team pictures for the lobby in Yost Ice Arena. He also was responsible for initiating the Dekers Hockey Hall of Fame in 1965, and has served on this committee all these years as its chairperson.
Doug timed the first collegiate hockey game ever played in Cobo Hall in Detroit when Michigan played the University of Toronto in 1962. He also timed the last hockey game in the Old Coliseum and the first game ever played in Yost Ice Arena. He still remembers Frank Werner scoring the first goal in Yost Ice Arena.
He has had many memorable Michigan hockey experiences and one that stands out was being in the locker room in Utica, NY during the 1962 NCAA Hockey Finals and coach Al Renfrew announced that Red Berenson would be playing his next game for the Montreal Canadiens.
Another high on his list was watching Michigan beat Denver in Denver for the 1964 NCAA Championship and having been adopted by the team as "Ambassador at Large".
The countless number of lifetime friends Doug has made through Michigan hockey is very special to him and he is "in his glory" whenever one may call or stop in Ann Arbor for a visit. They remain his closest friends today.
Doug and his wife Judy have five children; Nancy, Lucy, Trudi, Shelly, and Bill, and have four grandchildren.
This collection is comprised largely of material related to Barnett's involvement with the Dekers, the University of Michigan hockey booster club and scrapbooks relating to Barnett's employment with the University of Michigan Mail Service. The collection is arranged in the following series: Dekers Material, Hockey Media Material, Hockey Topical Files, Hockey Photographs and Negatives, Hockey Scrapbooks, and Mail Service Scrapbooks.
The majority of the hockey material is related to the Dekers Hall of Fame inductions. This includes copies of player biographies read at the induction ceremonies, as well as questionnaires the players themselves filled out, and related correspondence. Barnett was often involved in organizing team reunions, and gathering relevant material. His photo collection, primarily copies of university photos, spans the history of hockey at the University of Michigan, from the first teams in the 1920s to Hall of Fame induction ceremonies in the early 1990s. More than 60 individuals comprise the collection of player, manager, and coach photographs. Images of many of these individuals can also be found in the Hall of Fame series.
The three Mail Service Scrapbooks chronicle Barnett's employment with the University of Michigan Mail Service. The scrapbooks cover the period from 1948 to 1981. Included in the scrapbooks are photographs of mail service staff, equipment, facilities, staff events, and newspaper clippings.
Subjects:
Barnett, Douglas.; Ice hockey--Michigan.; Postal service--Michigan.; University of Michigan--Hockey.; University of Michigan--Employees.; Dekers Blue Line Club.; University of Michigan. University Mail Service.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Photographs.
- Dekers Material
  - Newsletters (Box 1)
  - Player Biographies for induction into Hall of Fame (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Questionnaires (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 1)
- Hockey Media Material
  - CCHA Press Releases (Box 1)
  - Team Statistics (Box 1)
  - U-M Hockey Press Releases, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Hockey Topical Files
  - Awards Banquet Programs (Box 1)
  - Conference Record Books (Box 1)
  - Memorable Events (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Team Information (Box 1)
  - Player Histories (Box 1)
  - Renfrew Retirement (Box 1)
  - Reunion Material (Box 1)
- Hockey Photographs and Negatives
  - Negatives
    - Team photos (undated) (Box 1)
    - Reunion -- 1974 (Box 1)
    - Hall of Fame induction ceremonies (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Dekers Hall of Fame, 7 photographs (Box 1)
    - Hall of Fame inductions
      - 1969
        - Doug Barnett presenting (uncertain as to recipient) (Box 1)
        - Group photo (Box 1)
      - 1975 Induction
        - Candids (Box 1)
        - Group photo (Box 1)
      - 1976
        - Merle Falk presenting with Dr. Sibilsky (Box 1)
      - 1977
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - James Haas and John Dale (Box 1)
        - Douglass Philpott and John Dale (Box 1)
        - John Dale and John McKennell (Box 1)
        - John Dale and Daniel Pettermann (Box 1)
        - Reg Shave and John Dale (Box 1)
        - John Dale and George Chin (Box 1)
      - 1978
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Alex MacLellan and Dave Burger (Box 1)
        - Dave Burger and Bob Heathcott (Box 1)
        - Dick Starrak and Dave Burger (Box 1)
      - 1979
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Randy Trudeau (Box 1)
        - Bob Pitts (Box 1)
        - Bill Lord (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Randy Trudeau (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Bob Pitts, 3 photographs (Box 1)
      - 1981
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Dale MacDonald, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Joe Lunghamer (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Bob Schiller (Box 1)
        - Bob Schiller (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Dick Dunnigan (Box 1)
        - Dick Dunnigan (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk and Paul Gambsy (Box 1)
        - Paul Gambsy (Box 1)
      - 1986
        - Kris Manery, Jack McDonald, Glen Williams (Box 1)
        - Jack McDonald and Glen Williams, 2 copies (Box 1)
      - 1988
        - Group photo (Box 1)
      - 1990
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Doug Barnett presenting to: (Box 1)
        - Robert Gray (Box 1)
        - Rudy Reichert (Box 1)
        - Joe Marmo (Box 1)
        - John Palenstein (Box 1)
      - 1991
        - Al Renfrew, John Sherf, and Gib James (Box 1)
        - Spike James, Fred Heddle, Rudy Reichert, "Gib", Art Schlanderer, and John Sherf (Box 1)
        - Bob White, Al, Gus Crouch, Doug (Box 1)
        - Spike James, Al, Dave Butts (Box 1)
        - "Gib", "Spike", Nate Weinberg (Box 1)
        - "Gib" and Fred Hatfield (Box 1)
        - Gib James (Box 1)
        - Mary and Gib James (Box 1)
        - "Gib" (Box 1)
        - Dave Butts and Fred Hatfield (Box 1)
        - Dave Bustfield, "Gib", Dave Butts, and Angie Moretto (Box 1)
        - Dave Butts and Fred Hatfield (Box 1)
        - Angie Moretto and Fred Hatfield (Box 1)
        - Dave Busfield, Gib James, Fred Hatfield (Box 1)
      - 1992
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Dave (Last Name?) presenting to: (Box 1)
        - Leonard Teitelbaum (Box 1)
        - Mike Martilla (Box 1)
        - Ted Speers (Box 1)
      - 1993
        - Group photo (Box 1)
        - Tom Lindskog, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Tim Manning, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Don Canham (Box 1)
        - Merle Falk (Box 1)
    - Individual Photos (taken by University photographers)
      - Players
        - Larry Babcock (Box 1)
        - Red Berenson, 7 photographs (Box 1)
        - Bob Boyson, 3 photographs (Box 1)
        - Al Brook, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Dave Butts (Box 1)
        - George Chin (Box 1)
        - Jack Cole, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Phil Cron (Box 1)
        - Dave Debol (Box 1)
        - Ron Deeks(??) (Box 1)
        - Paul Domm, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Dick Dunnigan (Box 1)
        - Robert Ferguson (Box 1)
        - Greg Fox (Box 1)
        - Bernie Gagnon, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Doug Galbraith, 3 photographs (Box 1)
        - Paul Gamsby (Box 1)
        - Phil Gross, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Jim Haas (Box 1)
        - Lars Hansen, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Jerry Hartman (Box 1)
        - Harold Herman (Box 1)
        - Dan Hoene (Box 1)
        - Carl Isaacson (Box 1)
        - Gib James (Box 1)
        - Steve Jones (Box 1)
        - Ben Kawa (Box 1)
        - William Kelly (Box 1)
        - Bruce Koviak (Box 1)
        - Bill Lord, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Dean Lucier, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Joe Lunghamer (Box 1)
        - Craig Malcolmson (Box 1)
        - Kris Manery (Box 1)
        - Tim Manning (Box 1)
        - Lee Marttila, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Mike Marttila (Box 1)
        - Dale McDonald, 4 photographs (Box 1)
        - Jack McDonald (Box 1)
        - John McGonigal, 3 photographs (Box 1)
        - Jim McKennell (Box 1)
        - Angie Moretto (Box 1)
        - Randy Neal (Box 1)
        - Greg Page (Box 1)
        - Rick Palmer (Box 1)
        - Dan Petermann (Box 1)
        - Doug Philpott (Box 1)
        - Bob Schiller (Box 1)
        - Tom Schiller, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Reg Shave (Box 1)
        - George Sibilsky (Box 1)
        - Brian Skinner (Box 1)
        - Ted Speers (Box 1)
        - Leonard Teitelbaum (Box 1)
        - Jeff Tessier (Box 1)
        - Mark Thompson, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Mel Wakabayashi, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Danny Walter (Box 1)
        - Aaron Ward (Box 1)
        - Unlabeled, 2 photographs (Box 1)
      - Pete Pinkus, Manager (Box 1)
      - Coaches
        - Dan Farrell (with Captain Randy Trudeau) (Box 1)
        - Vic Heyliger, 2 photographs (Box 1)
        - Al Renfrew, 2 photographs (Box 1)
          (includes 1 photograph with Mike Martilla)
    - Action photos, various games, 16 photographs (Box 1)
    - Team Photos
      - First team -- 1982 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Personal Photos and other miscellaneous items
      - #24, 2 photographs (Box 1)
      - Postcard of Red Berenson (Box 1)
      - Awards ceremony, 6 photographs (Box 1)
      - Reunion, 5 photographs (Box 1)
      - Letter and photos from Mel Wakabayashi (Box 1)
      - Unknown players (Box 1)
      - Referee with fish (Box 1)
      - Joe Marmo Ice Hockey Arena (photo) (Box 1)
      - Photo collage, 2 photocopies (Box 1)
      - Game photo (versus Wisconsin, undated) (Box 1)
- Hockey Scrapbooks (oversized)
  - Hockey 1 (Volume 1)
  - Hockey 2 (Volume 2)
  - Hockey 3 (Volume 3)
- Mail Service Scrapbooks
  - Volume 1 (Box 2)
  - Volume 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 3 (Box 2)